37 HOURS AGO
How's Hyun-su?
He lost his memory.
How much of it?
I'm not entirely sure.
Well, if that's the case,
I hope he lost all his bad memories too.
He wouldn't want that.
Without his memories…
he would really be a monster.
Ji-su.
I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
I don't think I can be with everyone
for much longer.
From now on, you have to be the one
who protects this place.
Protect the people here…
and Eun-yu.
ORIGINAL STORY WEBTOON SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
SWEET HOME
Make a left here.
GREEN HOME APARTMENTS
You can't be serious!
Why would we come back here?
Are you crazy?
This is a mistake.
Let's just go back.
To where?
What?
You saw that place.
Did it look safe to you?
Does this "shelter" even exist?
Why won't you tell us where it is?
We don't know if you're infected.
Anyone could be infected.
You're not immune to monsterization.
Anyone could turn into a monster.
You don't know when or how.
We can't…
go any further.
Wait here for a minute.
I'll be right back.
He might not be…
the Eun-hyeok you remember.
You're wrong.
He promised he'd come back.
No matter what.
I won't believe anything else…
until I see him with my own eyes.
Fuck.
You better think this through.
You're making a big mistake.
Is that a threat?
I got nothing to lose.
And this is how you threaten someone.
Damn it.
GREEN HOME
THE HOLY BIBLE
GREEN HOME RULES OF SURVIVAL
QUARANTINE THE INFECTED
SURVIVORS, TURNING, DEAD
TURNING: LEE EUN-HYEOK
I'll come back.
Don't worry.
I'll come back safe.
Just kill them.
With them out of the picture,
we're just innocent survivors.
Let's just kill these assholes
and be on our way!
It's as simple as that!
Choose wisely.
Don't you want the vaccine?
There's a vaccine?
It does say here
that a vaccine is being developed.
You took Hyun-su.
Then a vaccine can be made, right?
Not anyone can get it.
But maybe survivors who saved soldiers
from an armed assailant could.
-Hey, what are you doing?
-I can't fucking die like this!
Drop the gun!
Drop it!
You little bitch.
Get up.
Get up, you bitch.
Get the fuck up.
Come here.
Come here, you fucking bitch!
Fuck you!
Come here.
-You motherfucker!
-You need to see this.
There's nothing but corpses!
They're…
the Crow Platoon.
They're still warm.
It couldn't have been long.
There must be…
a monster nearby.
Tie them all up.
We're returning to the shelter.
-But the survivors…
-Do they look like survivors?
I swear I could kill all of them myself.
If they're lucky, they'll live.
But if they die, that's their fate.
I tried to help you, sir.
-You know that. Please take me.
-Get off me!
Please, sir!
Sergeant!
What are you waiting for?
Tie them up and get in!
I said let's go!
You want to die with them?
I kept the knots loose.
Once we leave, look for a place to hide.
Ms. Im?
It's Ms. Im.
But she turned into a monster.
What now?
I'm fucking sick
and tired of these monsters.
Fucking die already!
What was that for?
What?
I'm doing my job.
She was human, sir.
No, she's a monster.
If I say she is, she is.
Monster…
It's a monster.
Come on, get up.
And what if she isn't?
Does that even matter?
Sir.
This is a war.
And it has to be us humans that win
after killing all these fucking monsters!
I can't see…
I'll kill you…
Found you…
Let go.
Are you trying to get us killed?
Found you…
This is Crow One. We got a man down.
-Calling for medical support.
-Hurry up!
Keep going!
He's in a critical state.
Requesting medical support.
Have a few men guard the injured
and continue the mission.
Third floor's clear.
Entering the fourth floor.
Rescue the Third Platoon and extract.
Keep your eyes peeled!
Monster on your six!
Open fire!
This is Crow Four.
We've taken out the monster,
but five men are injured and two are dead.
Extract the Third Platoon's entry team
and join the main element
with the injured.
Recon, do we have eyes
on the Second Platoon?
You see anything?
The building is blocking the view.
No line of sight, sir.
Get back down.
We'll be going there.
Count us out.
Pack it up, UDT.
We're heading back.
What are you doing?
They're barely awake, sir.
They're starving, injured, and exhausted.
You heard them.
We lost our vehicle and we're out of ammo.
So what?
We abandon the Second Platoon?
Yes, abandon them.
Just abandon them.
Abandon the dead
and protect our men who are alive.
Hey, Seok-chan.
Yes, sir.
What did Central Command
tell us six hours ago?
To return immediately.
This is insubordination, sir.
Men who aren't UDT, you can come too.
I'll take responsibility
for my insubordination when I return.
But Sergeant First Class Kim,
how will you
take responsibility for yours?
Shoot me, sir.
You'll get us all killed anyway.
Do it.
Just like you did to your family.
Injured men and UDT,
return to base with Sergeant Kim.
Let's go.
That was Ms. Im, wasn't it?
I think so.
She's the mom
from Room 1504, right?
Yes.
Didn't she turn into a monster?
That's what you said earlier.
She did.
Was she resisting it like Hyun-su did?
That's right.
Her eyes didn't turn black or anything.
She just had human eyes.
But she was all naked.
She's a monster, not a human.
Well, she's a good monster!
-She protected us!
-All monsters are evil, okay?
They should all be killed.
No!
You're wrong!
You disrespectful punk.
Why are you yelling at a kid?
Ma'am, are you okay?
Ji-su.
Ji-su, are you okay?
No, thanks to you.
You were too reckless this time.
Eun-yu.
We're not here because we're luckier
or better than others.
We barely survived
at the cost of their lives.
Don't let them be in vain.
I'm sorry,
but I'm never giving up.
I haven't seen him for myself.
So Eun-hyeok is still alive to me.
And I'll find him no matter what.
What's going on?
Why did you stop?
There's a survivor.
Are you going to let him in?
That's a bad idea!
My duty is to bring survivors
to the shelter.
Why are you so committed
to a duty you didn't sign up for?
I'm scared.
Don't try to be a hero.
Let's just go, okay?
We won't tell anyone.
No one will know.
Let's just go.
But I'll know.
What are you…
Where are you headed?
The shelter.
BAMSEOM EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT BUREAU
We meet at last.
Thanks for coming,
Cha Hyun-su.
So?
What do I need to do?
You'll find out soon enough.
You seem to be cooperative.
Yes.
If it means…
all of this will end.
All right, Cha Hyun-su.
I believe in you.
Type Red.
Blood makes them aggressive.
Are you the savior
who can end all of this?
Show us what you've got.
Begin the first test on MH-5, Cha Hyun-su.
So MH-6 here was the special infectee
who kidnapped MH-5?
Yes, sir.
And he was shot to death?
Are you sure he's dead?
No vital signs whatsoever.
We double-checked.
He was definitely a monster,
so how is he dead?
Could it be a similar case to MH-1?
MH-1 didn't die,
but this one also doesn't show
any monster-like responses.
Blood, bone marrow,
skin tissue, pituitary gland…
Collect everything you can.
We have to compare them
to samples from MH-1.
MH-5 will be brought here soon.
Make sure to prepare for it.
It could be our last chance.
All the data and experience
we got from MH-6 and MH-1
must be applied to MH-5.
What are you doing?
Come on, Cha Hyun-su.
I know you can do it.
Stop!
Stop it!
I want to stop hurting.
Help me.
Help.
No.
He's human.
No!
Was it you
who told me to cooperate?
Was that you?
Why did you kill him?
Why the hell did you kill him?
He didn't attack me.
He was suffering.
You didn't have to kill him.
He had no value as a test subject,
so we discarded him.
Was it because he was a monster?
Because monsters must be killed?
How are you any different from them?
What exactly are you?
He used to go berserk
at the sight of blood.
Dozens of soldiers died at his hands.
But he stopped attacking
after a short brawl with you.
We've never seen a monster
show self-control until now.
Not once.
You…
What did you do to him?
What on earth did you do?
I don't know.
Well, then who does?
Try to remember.
This is why we brought you here.
Answer me first.
Can you develop…
a vaccine with my help?
I saw the flier that said a vaccine
could be made using special infectees.
Is that why you're here?
-Is it true?
-The vaccine's already been made.
But it's all gone now.
So make it again.
You just need me, right?
Would you be fine
even if you had to die?
I wouldn't be here
if I was afraid of death.
No, you'll probably beg me to kill you.
You already know.
The MHs' ability to regenerate
is like a blessing to us,
but it's a curse for you.
You can't die even if you want to.
You're a "Monster Human."
It has a nice ring to it, doesn't it?
I came up with it.
An MH, a monster…
Call me whatever you want.
I don't care.
You'll do better than the others.
I have a feeling
that a very special MH will be born.
Get some rest.
It'll be rough starting tomorrow.
One more mistake
and you'll set off the alarm.
Ms. Seo Yi-kyung?
He's in Area C5.
Follow me.
What's there?
Do you know me?
Right.
You don't know me, do you?
But I know you.
I'm Sang-won's friend.
Are you coming or not?
Why are you helping me?
For old times' sake?
They're headed
toward the research facility.
Split up and look for them.
There's no time.
You heard the man. Let's go.
He's still here.
In such…
a pitiful state.
Must have been a long trip,
but I don't know if he'll be able to talk.
He probably won't.
But who knows?
You're his fiancée.
Have you been waiting for me?
Statistically, reality sucks.
Ignorance is bliss, as they say.
Do you still want to see him…
even if he's a monster?
I just have to see how Sang-won responds
to seeing you again.
This kind of stimulus is hard to come by.
You're crazy.
What brings you soldiers--
How could I not make that audition?
What's wrong with my face?
It's so unfair.
So ridiculous.
I did well…
God damn it.
Mr. Soldier.
Mr. Soldier…
What's wrong?
I'm too scared to pee.
Stupid fucking audition…
Nothing's wrong with my face.
What's wrong with my face?
Fuck this shit.
How could I not make it?
How do I look?
Am I pretty?
Mister…
Something's wrong with your face.
Take a good look.
My face is perfect.
Does my face look weird?
I said, how do I look?
Am I pretty?
Am I--
Move.
Get out!
Don't shoot my face…
My face…
What's wrong with my face?
Let me see a mirror.
Why is my face…
I'm not pretty!
This is not my face!
My face!
Take a close look at my face.
Am I pretty?
You look fucking disgusting.
My face…
Not my face…
No…
My face…
Please wake up!
Su-yeong…
Su-yeong!
Subtitle translation by Ji-hun Lee
Modify by Blue-Bird™